AMANDA CLAIRE: So here's a little volt meter.
Actually this is a multimeter.
There are a lot of functions that this particular one can measure.
Basically, what it is, is it's a little gadget that measures how much voltage is flowing between 2 contacts and you use these little kinda contact points, these little wires to make that measurement.
So, you know, I wouldn't get too scared about a tool like this.
I know it sounds really technical.
Some circuit vendors work on project where it maybe is necessary to know how much voltage is flowing across the circuit board so that you might need to put a resistor in there or install a capacitor in.
I'm not going to be talking about that much during this series because we're kind of talking about introduction of circuit bending but that is something that you may need a volt meter for in the future to be able to really make a good measurements of you know, the amount of voltage that's flowing across different parts of the circuit so you can calculate whether you need a resistor or a capacitor there but all that aside, a volt meter is also really helpful for testing your batteries.
You ought to see if they're any good anymore.
One like this, basically, there's different kinds of volt meters.
This one has different kind of levels of sensitivity here, right?
So you know, we can set this...
I'll set this on 20, which means it will measure up to 20 volts on that setting.
And so, you know, I'll take this battery and I'll put you know, 1 on one side and 1 on the other.
Actually I need to look at this so let's see.
So, I put 1 on one side and 1 on the other and aha!
It measures 1.53 and so you don't think I'm making it up.
I'll show you.
Here's the battery and then we'll go like this and aha!
It is measuring 1.5 something. Okay? 1.5 something, which is you know, through no small coincidence, the voltage of a AA battery.
So, because this is measuring 1.5, that means this battery is still okay and it will still work for a little while.
And so, you can use this to kinda test a bunch of batteries and as long as they're kinda measure up at about 1.5 volts, give or take of a few millivolts, you can still use that battery.